I am a multidisciplinary designer with a curious mind, a meetup lover, I enjoy talking to people and see how they are solving problems, I try to provide a rich engaging and innovative user experience to the users and seek to simplify the relationship between them and the interactive products they use, taking into consideration business goals and technological constraints.

# **Work Experience**

Capgemini May, 2022 - Present

**UI UX Designer** 

Currently, I am working on a global project (SAUR), by managing specific needs through research, interviews, meetings with stakeholders, prototyping and wireframing, planning, documenting, assisting on the quality assurance and releases, building the design system, and also support the marketing team with materials. Working closely to the developper team and PMs during development and implementation. Making Web, responsive and mobile functional prototypes using Sketch.

Foliatech France Mar 2020 - May, 2022

**UI UX Designer** 

I led the design on a project from scratch (Axiobat), by prototyping the web and mobile app using adobe XD, creating the design system, making the logo and the graphic charter. I helped in an ongoing project (Artinove), by improving ergonomics, finding better solutions, tracking user workflows (using UXCam), reducing the number of clicks and rageclicks and improving processes. I made the social media and the stores designs too and the apps are now rated 4.5 and 4.9 in app store.

Paul & José Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

Web Designer

Worked in a multi-disciplinary team to design, envision and conceptualize many websites and mobile responsive prototypes, graphic charters, social media posts, videos, logos and printed visuals.

Actando Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

Graphic Designer

Created and designed pharmaceutical modules and slides that were presented by medical delegates, made many linkedin posts designs and created some logos with their graphical charters.

Webagile Internship Apr 2019 - May 2019

Graphic Designer

Helped in designing many showcase and E-Commerce websites, integrated them using Wordpress, created social media posts, logos, flyers, graphic motions, video editings and animations.

LMPS Internship Aug 2018

Graphic Designer

Designed community management (social media) posts and flyers.

**Freelance** 

Designer

Collaborated with many developper teams and managed a wide variety of cross-media projects involving branding, illustrations, logos, video editings, UI designs and web integration such as Radius.ma, LivCollect, La Casa del Com and many moroccan startups.

**Education** 

Bachelor's degree - FST SETTAT 2019 - 2020

In 2020 I've obtained the bachelor's degree in Multimedia and web developement

Associate's degree - OFPPT 2017 - 2019

Obtaining the associate's degree in multimedia and development techniques, (high honours).

**Certifications** 

Accenture - Certified UX Designer

2023

# Oussama Hraich UI UX Designer

#### Contact

+212 690 009 179

hraich.oussama@gmail.com

Portfolio link (-)

Casablanca, MA

## **Skills & Tools**

# Design

Sketch

Adobe XD

Figma

Wireframing

Responsive layout

Interactive Prototyping

UXCam

Photohop & Illustrator

HTML/CSS/JS

#### Research

Design thinking

Personas

**Usability Testing** 

Benchmarking

## Collaboration

Scrum & SAFe

Jira

Trello

Monday

Marvel

AzureDevOps

Excel - Sheets

# Languages

French

English

Arabic

